hey spring fans today we're going to
嘿，今天的春季球迷，我们要
talk about some of the new functional
谈论一些新功能
reactive end points inside of spring 5
Spring 5内部的反应性终点
now spring 5 is not here yet it'll be
现在 spring 5还没到呢
out first half of next year but they're
明年上半年，但他们
doing great early release candidates
做出色的早期发布候选人
that you can check out right now you can
您现在可以签出
kick the bits the really big feature
发挥真正的大功能
sort of like the killer feature I think
有点像我认为的杀手级功能
in spring 5 is the new reactive
在 spring 5是新的反应
programming support and up until now
编程支持，直到现在
that support has been basically a
支持基本上是
reimagining of the underpinnings of
重新构想的基础
Spring Framework and spring MVC itself
Spring Framework和Spring MVC本身
support a fully reactive pipeline so
支持完全反应性的管道，因此
basically we've retrofitted some of the
基本上我们已经改装了一些
existing spring MVC component model and
现有的Spring MVC组件模型和
put it on top of an a neti a net new
把它放在一个neti之上
neti based engine now you can use some
基于neti的引擎，现在您可以使用一些
of these reactive features in a sort of
这些反应性特征中的一种
degraded mode on top of the servlet 3.1
Servlet 3.1之上的降级模式
base container but the real power comes
基本容器，但真正的力量来了
when you drop into this neti based
当您进入此基于neti
engine this runtime that we've developed
为我们开发的运行时提供引擎
to support reactive workloads now the
现在支持被动式工作负载
benefit of porting over the the existing
移植到现有的好处
spring MVC components is that you can
Spring MVC组件是您可以
take your existing applications and move
利用现有的应用程序并移动
them over piecemeal and and that's all
他们零零碎碎，仅此而已
very well and good metal that's I'm sure
我确定很好，很好的金属
going to be an interesting interesting
会很有趣
topic for another discussion another day
换个话题再讨论
but today I want to talk about something
但今天我想谈谈
that spring reactive ninja Arion Poots
那个 Spring 的反动忍者Arion Poots
ma just dropped a few days ago he talked
妈妈几天前刚刚掉线
about they new functional reactive
关于他们新的功能反应
endpoints so if you saw this blog I
终结点，所以如果您看到这个博客，我
encourage you if you haven't seen this
鼓励您，如果您还没有看到这个
blog Anchorage area if you have seen it
博客Anchorage区域（如果已看到）
then read it again because it's really
然后再读一遍，因为它真的
really really key to what we're about to
对我们即将要做的事情真的很关键
do here today new and spring 5
今天在这里做，春季和 spring 5
functional web framework this is a
功能性网络框架，这是一个
different component model and for some
不同的组件模型和某些
for some people this is going to be
对于某些人来说，这将是
exactly what they wanted for a long time
正是他们长期以来想要的
right this is going to be very familiar
对，这将是非常熟悉的
to people who have worked for example
以工作的人为例
with a Skeletor Sinatra or even spark
与Skeletor Sinatra甚至火花
Java or other technologies like this I
Java或其他类似的技术
think it's a natural addition to spring
认为这是 Spring 的自然补充
MVC it's a very natural addition to what
MVC是一个非常自然的补充
we're trying to do with spring MVC which
我们正在尝试使用Spring MVC
is to be more powerful to provide a
要更强大，以提供
better
更好
and support you know mix-and-match
并支持您知道混搭
component models wherever appropriate so
组件模型在适当的地方
today we're going to go a little bit
今天我们要去一点
beyond what our ian did in his
超越了我们伊恩在他的著作中所做的
introductory blog post we're going to go
我们将要介绍的博客文章
ahead and build a simple spring boot
前进并构建一个简单的 spring boot
application now as a work is being done
现在正在申请工作
in an ongoing way on top of on top of
持续不断地
spring 5 there's also work being done in
spring 5也有工作要做
the spring boot team to integrate some
Spring Boot团队整合了一些
of the new bits into the auto
新位的自动
configurations for spring boot so the
spring boot 的配置，因此
experience is meant to be similar to
经验应该类似于
what you get right now if you're using
如果您正在使用，现在会得到什么
Tomcat or jetty or or undertow for
雄猫或码头或
example in an embedded mode you should
嵌入式模式下的示例
just be able to check a box and start up
只是能够选中一个框并启动
a spring boot application and have full
一个Spring Boot应用程序，并具有完整
access to the reactive runtime but as
访问反应式运行时，但作为
the functional endpoints that we're
我们的功能端点
about to discuss are pretty new will
即将讨论的是很新的意愿
forgo some of that auto configuration
放弃一些自动配置
but we'll we'll start with that auto
但我们将以该自动开始
configuration as the basis for our
配置是我们的基础
project and use that as a way to pull in
项目并将其用作引入方式
the right library so we're going to go
正确的库，所以我们要去
into start spring nao of course we're
进入 Spring ，我们当然是
going to build a beautiful reactive
要建立一个美丽的反应
application we use Springs reactive web
我们使用Springs反应网的应用程序
support that's experimental you can see
您可以看到的实验性支持
it's marked experimental here we'll use
这里标记为实验性的，我们将使用
MongoDB spring data not MongoDB
MongoDB Spring数据不是MongoDB
we'll use I think that'll do that that
我们会用我认为那会做到的
actually ought to be enough for us to
实际上应该足以让我们
get started so let's go ahead and hit
开始吧，让我们继续前进
generate and we'll get a new zip file
生成，我们将获得一个新的zip文件
we're just going to open up this the zip
我们只是要打开这个拉链
file and we'll get a new project and we
文件，我们将获得一个新项目，我们
can import it into a IDE
可以将其导入IDE
now the the spring reactive support the
现在Spring 反应性支撑
the auto-configuration is youthful
自动配置很年轻
because it brings in a few libraries
因为它带来了一些图书馆
that we need and it gives us an idea of
我们需要的，它使我们有了
what is required to get this stuff up
拿起这个东西需要什么
and working but we don't need all of
和工作，但我们不需要所有
these bits so actually we're going to
这些位，所以实际上我们要
take apart we're going to dismantle it
拆开我们要拆除它
you know remove it and we'll keep only
您知道将其删除，我们只会保留
the the bits that we need for this
我们需要的位
particular example kind of working
具体示例工作方式
outside of the sort of the rails right
在那种轨道之外
now okay so we're going to use a spring
现在好了，所以我们要用Spring
web reactive this is a spring framework
网络反应式，这是一个 Spring Framework
library here and we'll bring in the neti
图书馆在这里，我们将带来neti
buffer nettie is the i/o library that
缓冲网是I / O库
underpins a lot of reactives if read a
如果阅读
lot of reactive technologies and
许多反应技术和
implementations are is included we bring
包括实现，我们带来了
in the reactor neti library now this is
在反应堆洗手间库中，现在是
the project reactor right iota project
该项目反应堆权利IOTA项目
reactor dot IPC module that supports our
支持我们的反应堆点IPC模块
integration with Nettie for for an event
与Nettie集成以进行活动
vented based IO and will also bring in
通风的IO，也将带来
the Jackson data binding module right so
Jackson的数据绑定模块是这样的
Jackson data bind you must be able to
您必须能够绑定Jackson数据
spell it for this to work okay there we
拼写这个可以正常工作
are and that I think will do now again
是的，我想现在会再做一次
when you when this is final when it's GA
当你当这是最后的决定时
when you've got the actual bits you
当你有实际的位时
won't need to do nearly so much in fact
实际上不需要做太多事情
I expect that a lot of this will go away
我希望很多事情都会消失
in the very next release right this
在下一个发行版中
functional reactive stuff is very new so
功能性反应性材料非常新，所以
it hasn't been automatically integrated
尚未自动集成
for us but by choosing the spring
对我们来说，但是选择 Spring
reactive support we get the the
反应性支持，我们得到了
milestones we get this special
里程碑，我们得到这个特别
dependencies build one thing that you
依赖关系建立了一件事，你
should be aware of is if you
应该知道的是，如果你
accidentally neglect as I have to
偶然地忽视了我
specify spring boot to that o then
将 spring boot 指定为o
you're going to get a bad experience so
你会遇到不好的经历，所以
make sure you push this up to 2.0 build
确保将其推向2.0版本
- snapshot okay now what we're going to
-快照好了，现在我们要做什么
do is we're going to build a simple
我们要做的是建立一个简单的
application that uses MongoDB we're
使用MongoDB的应用程序
going to you know we're going to
去你知道我们要
do it as we would any kind of
尽我们所能去做
application we're going to build an
我们将要构建的应用程序
entity I'll build an entity here
我将在这里建立一个实体
borrowing from our Ian's example in the
借鉴我们伊恩（Ian）的例子
blog an entity of type person so I'll
博客类型人的实体，所以我会
use the spring data document annotation
使用spring数据文档注释
here and we'll we'll create a string for
在这里，我们将为创建一个字符串
an ID right that's a very natural
很自然的ID权利
document ID
文件编号
unlike JDBC JP rather where you you
与JDBC JP不同，您在哪里
might use an ID like long MongoDB
可能会使用长MongoDB之类的ID
prefers strings for for auto
首选自动字符串
incrementing unique values and we're
增加唯一值，我们
going to give it a name value field and
将给它一个名称值字段，并
we'll give it a an age we'll give the
我们给它一个年龄，我们给
person named okay and a constructor and
名为okay的人和构造函数，以及
another constructor although I'm not
另一个构造器，尽管我不是
even sure if we need that and some
甚至确定我们是否需要
getters naturally and the to string for
吸气剂自然而然地
user debugging very good so now we have
用户调试非常好，所以现在我们有了
that and we want to be able to read and
那，我们希望能够阅读和
work with in two entities of this type
与两个这种类型的实体一起工作
so I'll create a repository I'll say
所以我会说一个仓库
extends Mongo repository and I'm going
扩展Mongo存储库，我要去
to manage entities of type person whose
管理类型为person的实体
primary key is a type string there we
主键是一个类型字符串
are and I'm going to want to iterate
是，我将要迭代
through potentially unlimited amounts of
通过可能无限量的
data large amounts of data so I'm going
数据量很大，所以我要去
to take advantage of a feature that's
充分利用
already in spring data since last year a
自去年以来已经在 spring data 中a
feature that lets me define finder
让我定义取景器的功能
methods using deferred or stream based
使用延迟或基于流的方法
types so I can say for example that I
类型，例如，我可以说
want to get a stream of person and I
想得到一连串的人和我
want to find all of them right so I'll
想找到所有正确的人，所以我会
just say all I'll provide a custom query
只是说我将提供自定义查询
like this using the MongoDB piece on
像这样在MongoDB上使用
query syntax for everything basically
基本查询所有内容的语法
and I want to get a specific finder on a
我想在一个特定的取景器上
specific person so I'll say give me a
具体的人，所以我说给我一个
completable future write both of these
可以完成的未来都写这两个
cases map naturally to the world of
案例自然地映射到
reactive programming so we'll will
反应性编程，所以我们将
exploit those here for our benefit okay
为我们的利益利用这里的人好
now we want to create some records as
现在我们想创建一些记录为
always so I'm going to create some
总是这样，我要创建一些
sample data I'll say class sample data
样本数据我会说课样本数据
CLR implement command line Runner and
CLR执行命令行Runner和
will override the the command line
将覆盖命令行
render interface providing a callback
渲染接口提供回调
here
这里
we'll inject our person repository so
我们将注入人员存储库，以便
that we have it so that we have it to
我们拥有它，以便我们拥有它
work with now in spring 4.3 and beyond
从4.3春季及以后开始使用
we don't need this auto wired annotation
我们不需要此自动连线注释
so I actually I'm I'm trying to remember
所以我实际上是想记住
to leave it off but I realized that a
离开它，但我意识到
lot of us are still accustomed to having
我们很多人仍然习惯于
to add it so maybe I should just leave
添加它，所以也许我应该离开
it I don't know who we'll see how that
我不知道我们会怎么看
goes as I do more of these so stream of
当我做更多这些事情时，
and we'll create some records so my name
我们将创建一些记录，以便我命名
is Josh naturally nice to meet you
乔希自然很高兴认识你
good to meet you I'm joined of course by
很高兴认识你，我当然也加入了
my heroes and friends Stefan Maldini the
我的英雄和朋友史蒂芬·马尔蒂尼
project lead of reactor which of course
反应堆项目负责人
underpins the WebSocket support and
支持WebSocket和
spring up for and underpins a reactive
涌现并支持反应
web runtime and spring 5 so very very a
Web运行时和Spring 5非常非常
pivotal guy and then of course our en
关键人物，当然还有我们
puts ma who who's a amazing blog post
放马谁谁是一个了不起的博客文章
set me off on this course rawson story
使我着迷于这个课程的罗森故事
on cheve another spring web ninja there
在爱上另一个 Spring 的网络忍者
we go that's a that's a small maybe we
我们去那是一个很小的也许我们
should add a few norm few more why not
应该添加一些规范，为什么不更多
right the one thing that's worth
对一件事值得
underscoring is that we could very well
强调我们可以很好
handle millions of records with the
使用
approach that we're about to investigate
我们将要研究的方法
so my simple sample data is just for
所以我的简单样本数据仅用于
it's just that it's just sample data ok
只是样本数据而已
so for each name we're going to save a
因此，对于每个名称，我们将保存一个
record in the database here we're going
记录在数据库中，我们要
to say person repository at save new
说保存新的人资料库
person and we'll pass in the name and
人，我们会输入名称和
we'll pass in an ID I don't want to pass
我们会传递一个我不想传递的ID
in the name and the constructor here
在这里的名称和构造函数中
until the day thank you rather the idea
直到那天，谢谢你的主意
I want to pass that in so we'll say name
我想通过它，所以我们说名字
and I'll use a new random to get a
我将使用新的随机数来获得
random int there we are and there we go
我们在那里，我们去那里的随机整数
so there's my my sample records and that
所以有我的样本记录
is I think enough right we now have the
我认为我们现在有足够的权利了吗
everything we need to to work with
我们需要合作的一切
MongoDB and to see that reflected on the
MongoDB并看到它反映在
console for one two so I can say find
一两个控制台，所以我可以说找到
all for each system that out print line
所有用于打印线的系统
so I'm going to basically use a method
所以我将基本上使用一种方法
reference
参考
of a metal reference to iterate to the
金属引用以迭代到
results and this is by the way I think a
结果，顺便说一句，我认为
key distinction for these component
这些组件的主要区别
models a lot of what we're doing here in
模仿了我们在这里所做的很多事情
the reactive stuff and the java DSL the
反应性的东西和Java DSL
java configuration DSL for spring
春季的Java配置DSL
integration the spring security stuff a
整合spring security的东西
lot of a lot of the really cool things
很多非常酷的事情
that we're doing we're able to do in
我们正在做的，我们能够做的
spring these days are because spring you
Spring ，这几天是因为 Spring ，你
know the rather java 8 is so big with
知道相当的Java 8这么大
its it's so popular so big written and
它是如此受欢迎，如此大的书面和
it's such an obviously good idea right
这是一个显而易见的好主意吧
there's so many good features in there
有很多好的功能
including lambdas so that it lets us
包括lambda，以便让我们
build a lot of DSL that would otherwise
建立大量的DSL，否则
be their own exclusive purview of other
成为其他人的专属权限
languages so I'm very happy to see this
语言，所以我很高兴看到这个
approach becoming more prominent so
方法变得更加突出
there we go there's our records in the
我们去那里有我们的记录
database now let's set up a simple REST
数据库，现在让我们建立一个简单的REST
API we're going to we're going to do
我们将要使用的API
that using a custom server we have to
使用自定义服务器，我们必须
stand up a server here and again this is
在这里站起一台服务器，这又是
not something you're going to have to
不是你必须要做的
expect to do too often right you're not
期望经常做，对吧？
going to do that too often but we need
经常这样做，但是我们需要
to do it this time so we'll create a
这次要做，所以我们将创建一个
server and our server will need an HTTP
服务器，我们的服务器将需要一个HTTP
handler and we can create a a handler by
处理程序，我们可以通过创建一个处理程序
passing in a router function and this is
传递路由器功能，这是
what we need to define but for now let's
我们需要定义什么，但现在让我们
assume that that's been defined here
假设已在此处定义
pretty quickly that it will be defined
很快它将被定义
we'll just carry on defining this HTTP
我们将继续定义该HTTP
server so we're going to define a
服务器，因此我们将定义一个
handler that will take it's sort of
需要的处理程序
directives from this router that we're
来自此路由器的指令
going to build this router function
要建立这个路由器功能
which is the the route if you will of
如果您愿意，这就是路线
our functional spring MVC endpoints okay
我们的功能性Spring MVC端点还可以
and then we would create an H to be
然后我们将创建一个H
server here when I an HP server passing
当我经过HP服务器时，服务器在这里
in a custom port right 8080 or there we
在自定义端口8080或那里
go and naturally this is you know this
走，自然这就是你知道的
is the kind of stuff you would put in a
是你会放进去的东西
property file or or you might even just
属性文件，或者甚至可能只是
inject server properties right the
注入服务器属性
spring boot server properties here and
Spring Boot Server属性在这里和
you could say serve it up properties
你可以说服务起来
duck in port right that would actually
潜入港口的权利，实际上
give us something so if we look at the
给我们一些东西，所以如果我们看看
default server properties here we can
默认服务器属性，我们可以
see
看到
at the default port is as yet
在默认端口上
unspecified is that true so maybe we
未指明是真的，所以也许我们
shouldn't lean upon this if the value is
如果值是
unspecified in spring but-- then spring
在春季未指定，但在春季
uses the socket utils to find an
使用套接字工具找到一个
otherwise unused port and time but for
否则未使用的端口和时间，但是
our purposes that's a little much let's
我们的目的是让我们
just keep it simple so we can understand
只要保持简单就可以理解
what's happening here okay so 8080 there
这里发生了什么事，所以那里8080
you go good and now we need to start the
你走的很好，现在我们需要开始
server by using a new reactive HTTP
通过使用新的反应式HTTP服务器
handler adapter we're going to adapt our
处理程序适配器，我们将适应我们的
custom hand right here and we're going
自定义手就在这里，我们要去
to return the server HTTP server and
返回服务器HTTP服务器，并
there we go that's our that's the the
我们去那是我们的那是
simple machinery and again there's a lot
简单的机械，还有很多
of other things we could do here what
我们可以在这里做的其他事情
we've created is an HTTP engine this is
我们创建的是一个HTTP引擎
the reactor HTTP server component this
反应器HTTP服务器组件
is from project reactor itself and then
来自项目反应堆本身，然后
the runtime the sort of the component
运行时组件的种类
model that reactive the reactive spring
反应Spring 的模型
component model is being provided here
此处提供组件模型
by this reactive HTTP handler adapter
通过此反应式HTTP处理程序适配器
and the HTTP handler here right now
和HTTP处理程序在这里
let's talk about the riad of the router
让我们来谈谈路由器的里亚德
functions that's the real meat of this
功能才是真正的本源
particular sandwich that's the stuff
特别的三明治就是那个东西
that we care about here right so we're
我们在这里关心，所以我们
going to say we're going to find a
会说我们要找到一个
router absurd router function and to do
路由器荒唐的功能和路由器做
so we need to return a route like so and
所以我们需要返回一条这样的路线
we're going to do the long-form version
我们将做长版
of this using the fully qualified static
使用完全限定的static
method in classes but you then will see
类中的方法，但随后您将看到
that it this DSL becomes much cleaner
DSL变得更干净了
once you strip away the sort of static
一旦你消除了那种静态
method references by using static
使用静态方法引用
imports okay so we're going to use get
导入还可以，所以我们将使用get
persons okay this becomes this is
人们好吧，这变成这是
actually request predicate 2 so there's
实际要求谓词2所以
that that's the long form version of
那是
that and then what it's expected is a a
那然后是预期的
lambda to handle the request that
lambda处理该请求
arrives
到达
at person's any request right we can be
根据个人的任何要求，我们可以
more specific of course and we can
当然更具体，我们可以
specify lots of different routes so here
指定很多不同的路线，所以在这里
we can say and request predicates dot
我们可以说并要求谓词点
route dot get rather person's ID and
路线点获取确切的人的ID和
then we specify every lambda to handle
然后指定每个要处理的lambda
that request as well okay so I'm right
这个要求也好，所以我是对的
now I'm passing in just a very just
现在我传递的只是一个非常公正的
default lambdas here which will not work
默认的lambdas在这里不起作用
naturally this won't work but we can fix
自然这是行不通的，但是我们可以修复
that once we've got the sort of
一旦我们有了那种
scaffolding done I find it helps to to
脚手架做完了，我发现它有助于
flesh out what we want to do here first
充实我们想在这里做什么
and then provide the actual definitions
然后提供实际的定义
for those lambdas or those definite you
对于那些lambda或那些确定的你
know those objects and we'll do that
知道那些对象，我们会做的
actually in another class that's another
其实在另一个班上
reason that it's not particularly
原因不是特别
valuable to to implement that code right
对实施该代码很有价值
here because it becomes kind of an
在这里，因为它变成了一种
eyesore right so so there we go this is
眼睛很对，所以我们要去的是
our simple you know mapping if you will
如果您愿意，我们会告诉您简单的映射
this is this is a lot a lot of doing
这是很多事情
here's what would have done it in sort
这是应该做的事情
of a handler mapping in spring MVC now I
现在在Spring MVC中处理程序映射的说明
can do a lot more of course I can for
当然可以做得更多
example use other predator can further
例如使用其他掠食者可以进一步
predicate my requests you know I can
断言我的请求你知道我可以
further constrict the qualifying
进一步压缩排位赛
requests and I can say for example
请求，我可以说例如
request predicates dot accepts media
请求谓词点接受媒体
type application JSON right so the the
正确输入应用程序JSON，因此
I'm only going to in this case I'm only
我只会在这种情况下
going to respond to two incoming client
要响应两个传入的客户端
that will accept the application Jason
将会接受Jason的申请
type for media okay it becomes a little
媒体类型好吧，它变得有点
redundant in our case to do that so
在我们看来，这样做是多余的
we'll just leave it off but suffice it
我们就不用管它了，但是就足够了
to say there's a lot of power there now
说那里现在有很多力量
let's talk about those Lando's let's
让我们来谈谈那些兰多吧
talk about these implementations i Arion
在Arion谈论这些实现
had a good idea in the blog he factored
在他认为的博客中有一个好主意
out allow this code into a separate
允许将此代码放入单独的
class and then he just reused that as he
上课，然后他就重用了
was developing a the example and i think
在开发一个例子，我认为
it's a good idea because it makes it
这是一个好主意，因为它做到了
easier to test it's more approachable
测试起来更容易
and it removes a lot of the business
它消除了很多生意
logic away from the routing definitions
逻辑远离路由定义
right so we're going to create we don't
对，所以我们要创建我们不
do the same thing here
在这里做同样的事情
knowing that we're going to have to
知道我们将不得不
provide two methods for these different
为这些不同提供两种方法
end points we're great a custom class
终点，我们很棒的自定义课程
here called a person handler okay so
这里叫人经理好吧
let's say class person handler and we
假设是班级人员经理，我们
have to respond with a response let's
必须回应，让我们
the spring reactive payload if you will
Spring 反应有效载荷，如果您愿意
the envelope payload for the response
响应的信封有效载荷
that we're going to send back and we're
我们要寄回去，
going to we're going to this is going to
去我们要去这将要
be a method that will handle all the
可以处理所有
records right and then we have another
记录正确，然后我们有另一个
one that will respond with just just the
一个只会回应
by ID record so let's with that in mind
通过ID记录，因此请记住这一点
we don't with that in mind the all
我们全都没有考虑到这一点
method is going to be turn every
方法将被轮流
instance of a person in the reactive
一个人在反应堆中的实例
world what we're trying to do is not
我们想要做的世界不是
we're not trying to return a collection
我们不试图返回收藏
remember we're trying to return an
请记住，我们正在尝试返回
object that represents a potentially
代表潜在的对象
endless stream of values so a collection
无休止的价值流，所以一个集合
isn't a great fit we're trying to return
我们尝试退货并不适合
potentially endless stream of values
潜在的无休止的价值流
that that will give us a notification
那会给我们通知
when new values are available right so
当新值可用时，这样
so in the reactive streams API their
因此在反应式流API中
active streams API is a is an implicit
活动流API是一个隐式
sort of a agreed upon language for
某种商定的语言
describing reactive back pressure it's
描述它的反作用背压
something - - which pivotal and other
东西--关键和其他
stakeholders like light Bend who are the
像Light Bend这样的利益相关者
progenitors of ibaka and red hat with
ibaka和红色帽子的祖先
their with their vertex and Netflix with
他们的顶点和Netflix
RX RX java 1.0 which of course doesn't
RX RX Java 1.0当然不会
have reactive streams implementation
具有反应流实施
support but well in reactive streams the
支持但在反应流中很好
Roderick's java rather - dot o all these
Roderick的Java而不是-所有这些
signatories sort of define the language
签名者定义语言
of of reactive streams and backpressure
反应流和反压
and it did so so good a job at that that
在那方面做得很好
base definition is now part of the JDK 9
基本定义现在是JDK 9的一部分
effort so JDK 9 Java 9 will have a Java
因此JDK 9 Java 9将拥有Java
util concurrent flow package based on
util并发流程包基于
the sort of work done in this this this
在这个这个做的工作
description this is this document okay
说明这是这份文件还可以
so in that world we have this idea of a
所以在那个世界里，我们有一个
publisher and a publisher can publish it
发布者，发布者可以发布它
it's a it's a potentially unbounded
这是一个潜在的无限
of values that can publish either zero
可以发布或为零的值
or a bazillion write an infinite number
或不计其数的数字
of values there are specializations of
价值观有专业化
those four for convenience inside of the
为了方便起见，这四个
reactor project write our reactor
反应堆项目写我们的反应堆
project reactor reactor three dado in
项目反应堆反应堆三达多在
specific and so if we're going to return
具体的，所以如果我们要返回
return a stream of one or more values
返回一个或多个值的流
that's called a flux
这就是所谓的通量
okay so flux of person and of course two
好吧，人流当然是两个
to handle the to handle the response to
处理响应
handle serving a response we need to
处理我们需要的回应
interrogate and work with the request so
询问并处理请求，以便
we'll pass that in here okay make that a
我们将其传递给这里，好使
no for now and then same thing here
现在暂时没有
except instead of returning a flux we're
除了不返回通量，我们
going to return just one object one
将只返回一个对象
value one or zero value is basically
值一或零值基本上是
it's either there or it's not but it's
它在那儿，或者不是，但那是
not going to be more than one value and
不会超过一个值，并且
in the in the reactor world this is
在反应堆世界中，这是
called a mono both implement both are
都叫做单声道工具，两者都是
subclasses of publisher okay so we we
发布者的子类好，所以我们
get all all the understanding that we
得到所有我们的理解
have by using the right two streams API
通过使用正确的两个流API
we get all that with benefit from all
我们从所有人那里受益
that but we're we're able to do more
那，但是我们有能力做更多
interesting things now that we know we
现在我们知道我们有趣的事情
have a certain bound we understand the
有一定的界限，我们了解
constraints of the data that we'll get
我们将获得的数据约束
we may we may have okay so for the all
我们可能会没事的，所以对于所有人
method and for the by ID method
方法和按ID方法
you know we've stubbed it out as we as
你知道我们已经把它存根了
we were trying to do now we can reuse
我们正在尝试做，现在我们可以重复使用
that Handler we can tell spring to put
我们可以告诉Spring的处理程序
that you know to inject that object to
您知道要将该对象注入
make it available as a a parameter here
在此处将其用作aa参数
so we'll say handler all okay and then
所以我们会说处理程序一切正常，然后
we'll say handler by ID now we're using
我们将使用ID说出处理程序
method references here and I think
方法参考这里，我认为
that's very clean right we're not
那很干净对，我们不是
worrying about the business logic we
担心我们的业务逻辑
just know that this lambda is going to
只是知道这个lambda要
be invoked and we can we can much more
被调用，我们可以做更多
readily test this I think that's a nice
随便测试一下，我认为这很好
compromise between sort of the spring
在 Spring 之间折衷
MVC clip the classic spring MVC
MVC剪辑经典的春季MVC
component model and the stuff we're
组件模型以及我们所需要的东西
doing here now the all use case is
现在在这里做的所有用例是
pretty
漂亮
darn simple isn't it right we just need
简单，不是吗，我们只需要
to take the data coming from our person
从我们的人那里获取数据
repository and send it back as a request
存储库，并根据请求将其发送回
and I'll inject I'll provided an
然后我将提供一个
explicit constructor there so we say a
显式构造函数，所以我们说一个
person repository dot all and we get a
人员存储库全部点缀，我们得到一个
stream so what I want to do is I want to
流，所以我想做的就是
take this I want to take that stream and
采取这个我想采取的流和
then adapt it into a flux right so I'll
然后将其调整为通量，这样我就
say give me a flux and then I need to
说给我一个通量，然后我需要
wrap the resulting value there the
将结果值包装在那里
resulting value I want to wrap that in a
结果值我想把它包装在
response and then send that back so we
回应，然后将其发送回去，所以我们
can say now response dot okay and you
可以说现在响应点还可以
know naturally there are other builder
自然知道还有其他建造者
methods here okay bad requests not not
这里的方法还可以，不好的要求不是
found etc this is very similar to the
发现等等，这非常类似于
spring MBC respond to entity so you'll
春季MBC回应实体，您将
you know it's very natural to move back
你知道回去很自然
and forth between one program model and
在一个程序模型和
the other I will say response not okay
其他我会说回应不好
dot and we need to create a body now
点，我们现在需要创建一个主体
remember this is and then this is an
记住这是然后这是一个
engine that's optimized for dealing with
针对处理而优化的引擎
potentially unlimited amounts of data so
可能无限量的数据，因此
our notion of a response body the
我们对回应主体的概念
content length a lot of these things
这些东西的内容长度很多
that we've taken for granted in
我们理所当然地认为
traditional HTTP these things have to be
传统的HTTP这些东西必须
rethought a little bit in particular
特别考虑一下
what does it mean to stream JSON right
正确传输JSON是什么意思
with with with JSON we don't really know
与JSON一起使用，我们真的不知道
if we're at a sort of a chunk of data
如果我们有大量的数据
naturally so there's extra work that has
自然地，所以有额外的工作
to be done underneath in the engine in
在引擎下面做
the rendering for this JSON and we've
JSON的渲染，我们已经
done that of course but for now that a
当然可以做到，但是就目前而言
lot of that stuff sort of surfaces in
这些东西很多
terms of this this body inserter
这个身体插入器的条款
interface right so we're going to use
界面正确，因此我们将使用
that here we're going to say body
在这里我们要说身体
inserters dot and we're going to create
插入点，我们将创建
an inserter based on a publisher so
基于发布者的插入器
we're going to write data to the body
我们将数据写入身体
when it cert data into the body by
当它通过以下方式将数据验证到正文中时
consuming data coming off of that flux
消耗来自该流量的数据
okay so flex there we are and
好吧，我们在那里弯曲
that should do cannot resolve method Oh
那应该解决不了的方法哦
the other thing we need to do is like I
我们需要做的另一件事就是像我
say we need to give it a frame right we
说我们需要给它一个框架，我们
need to this is very similar to TCP or
需要这个非常类似于TCP或
classic TTP and classic network
经典TTP和经典网络
programming we have a message frame now
编程我们现在有一个消息框
right because we're streaming a
对，因为我们正在流式传输
potentially unlimited amount of data we
我们可能无限量的数据
need to help the framework itself frame
需要帮助框架本身框架
the data and it needs to do that in
数据，它需要这样做
terms of how you know what it means to
您如何知道这意味着什么的术语
be one person in a collection of people
在一个人中成为一个人
basically a an unlimited stream of
基本上是无限的
people so that's the the boundary that's
人，这就是边界
why we have to provide this not because
为什么我们必须提供这个不是
of generics but because that now this
泛型，但因为现在
other method this is a little bit more
其他方法多一点
interesting because we don't know we
有趣，因为我们不知道我们
hope right we expect that we're going to
希望对了，我们期望我们将
have a ID a parameter here a path
有一个ID一个参数这里是一个路径
variable that's passed in is an ID so
传入的变量是一个ID，因此
let's write that code with the
让我们用
assumption that that may not be there so
假设可能不存在
we'll say request dot path variable ID
我们说请求点路径变量ID
and if it's there what we get back is a
如果在那里，我们得到的是
Java 8 optional right so ID optional or
Java 8可选权，因此ID可选或
do you say optional map ID and then we
您说可选的地图ID，然后我们
can say that we want to get the data
可以说我们要获取数据
from the repository so we'll get the
从存储库中，所以我们将获得
find it by ID passing in this ID here
通过在此传递ID的ID找到它
and if we find it then we want to map
如果我们找到它，那么我们想映射
that into a into a a mono so we're going
变成一个单声道，所以我们要
to say people or person mono dot from
说人或人的单点
future because we're going to get a
未来，因为我们将获得
computer completable future here right
电脑可以在这里完成的未来
uh where's our interface here a
呃我们的界面在哪里
completable future passing this in and
可以完成的未来
then if we don't you know then we if we
然后，如果我们不知道，那么我们是否
if we had that we want to then create a
如果我们想创建一个
response to to hold it right it just as
保持正确的回应
we did before so we'll say the mono will
我们之前做过，所以我们会说单声道会
be wrapped using response okay dot body
使用响应好点体包裹起来
and and here we're going to use the body
在这里，我们将使用身体
in searchers again from publisher mono
在搜索者中再次从发布商Mono获得
and again when you do the
当你做
medication there the framing if you will
如果你愿意的话，在那里服药
and then with that we should be able to
然后我们应该能够
do should be all we have one more thing
要做的就是我们还有一件事
to do we need to handle the situation
我们需要处理情况
where it's not there so that's the or
不存在的地方就是
else throw sort of Clause we're going to
否则抛出一些条款，我们要
say if we cannot find it
说如果我们找不到
if we cannot load the data we should
如果我们无法加载数据，我们应该
throw a proper custom exception but
抛出适当的自定义异常，但
let's just let's just argue that we
让我们只是说说我们
don't have the right state
没有正确的状态
oops there we go so I encourage you to
哎呀，我们走了，所以我鼓励你
do an infinitely better job than I have
做得比我好得多
here now we we can see that the ID is
现在我们可以看到ID为
offering to help us here wants to help
提供帮助我们在这里想要帮助
us really really badly look at the uses
我们真的很不好看用途
of things that could otherwise be method
本来可以作为方法的事物
references and and look no they static
引用，并且看起来不，它们是静态的
import so we'll come back to that in a
导入，因此我们将在
second but let's confirm that everything
其次，让我们确认一下
is working shall we let's go ahead and
正在工作，让我们继续前进，
start it up and localhost:8080 and what
启动它和localhost：8080以及什么
did we say we called it the person's
我们是不是说我们称呼这个人的
endpoint so persons whoops it's not one
终结点，所以人们大呼这不是一个
because that ID doesn't exist it's these
因为那个ID不存在就是这些
names here glad to eat that one there we
这里的名字很高兴在那里吃那个
are so there's the record just right I I
所以有唱片就在我身旁
can look up the data as much as I want I
可以根据需要查找尽可能多的数据
get the results as I expect so let's go
得到我期望的结果，让我们开始吧
back to our data now let's let's go back
回到我们的数据现在让我们回到
to our code and just clean it up a
到我们的代码，然后清理它
little I think we're in a good place and
我想我们在一个好地方，
I think you can already see how it's
我想你已经知道了
very natural to to work with the spring
很自然地适应 Spring
data support and mix and match that with
数据支持，并将其与
the reactive API is now a few things to
现在，反应式API可以
say about that react to support in the
说说对支持的反应
spring data modules first of all that's
Spring 数据模块首先是
limited to just a subset of the modules
仅限于模块的一个子集
that support reactive API so in spring
支持响应式API，因此在春季
that itself you can use it with
本身，您可以使用它
Couchbase with MongoDB with JPA but this
具有JPA的MongoDB和Couchbase，但这
sort of depends on the underlying
取决于底层
implementation and you're not going to
实施，您不会
always have reactive semantics and maybe
总是有反应性语义，也许
you'll have streaming semantics which is
您将拥有流式语义，即
still better than you know select all
比您知道的还要好选择所有
sort of
有点
approach but it's not exactly the same
方法，但并不完全相同
thing there's some interesting news that
事情有一些有趣的消息
just came out of Java one last week
上周刚从Java出来
Oracle has announced that they're
甲骨文宣布他们
working on a sort of not an extension to
在某种程度上不是对
JDBC but another project on a parallel
JDBC，但另一个并行项目
effort to introduce reactive programming
努力引入反应式编程
support for database drivers right I'm
我对数据库驱动程序的支持
not sure if that's JDBC itself or its if
不知道这是JDBC本身还是
it if it's a side side branch or
它是侧面分支还是
something like that but but the point is
那样的东西，但重点是
evidently they're at least thinking
显然他们至少在想
about this as well so this could this
关于这个，所以这可能
could bode very well for those of us who
对于我们中的那些人来说可能是个好兆头
are trying to work with a reactive you
试图与一个被动的你一起工作
know sequel databases okay now we are
知道续集数据库好了，现在我们
going to remove this so we'll say add
要删除它，所以我们说添加
on-demand static import for the router
路由器的按需静态导入
functions Cray that helps considerably
实用的Cray功能
add on demand for requests predicates
按需添加谓词
great that helps considerably and I
极大的帮助，我
think you agree that's not actually that
以为你同意那实际上不是
bad at this point right that becomes a
在这一点上不好，变成一个
very clean one-liner so there's that and
很干净的一线，所以有
down here we can use method references
在这里，我们可以使用方法引用
here okay and there we go not bad and I
在这里还可以，我们还不错，我
can even use this I can use a just met I
甚至可以用这个我可以用我刚刚见过的
can use a on-demand statics for the for
可以使用for的按需静态
the predicate here as well okay up that
这里的谓词也可以
I think my friends is a is a quick look
我想我的朋友是一个快速的眼神
at the reactive functional endpoints and
在反应性功能端点和
spring MVC five I hope you'll go to
春季MVC五个，希望您能参加
startup spring that IO and and kick the
启动Spring ，IO，并踢
get the bit and kick the tires if you
得到一点点，如果你踢轮胎
will check out our Ian's amazing blog
将查看我们伊恩的精彩博客
and stay tuned for four more of these
并继续关注其中的四个
videos thanks for much
视频非常感谢
you
您